RAYMOND **JOHNSON**

JAVASCRIPT ENGINEER

EDUCATION

Interaction Design College for Creative Studies - Detroit, MI 2016 - 2018

LANGUAGES / LIBS

React	
Redux	
Javascript	
Typescript	
Es6	
Node.Js	
jQuery	
HTML 5	
CSS 3	
PostgreSQL	
REST	
Jest - testing	
Mobile First	
PHP	

TOOLING

Webpack Babel Git Heroku

Other

Agile / Scrum
Continuous Deployment
Test Driven Development

27123 Charles Ct. Southfield, MI

t: +1 (313) 214 - 5703

e: raymondjohnson121@gmail.com **w:** raymond-jay.herokuapp.com github.com/rayjohnson1

in linkedin.com/in/rayjohnson141

medium.com/@raymondjohnson121

ABOUT ME

Advanced javascript engineer with expertise in Node.Js and React. I combine my front end engineering skills with my interaction design background to create elegant and interactive user interfaces while adhering to a familiar design hierarchy for a straight forward, easy-to-use user experience.

MY PROCESS

In my current freelance work, my goal is quick, efficient delivery, and this is made possible through constant interactions with clients and working in an agile/scrum environment for quick iterative updates. This process process has proved to keep my clients happy while making sure the freshest version of the product is done and released.

WHAT I BRING TO YOU

As a front end engineer, the value that I will bring to you is the level of competency that I have built through my readings, writings and working with real clients. I love to engage with colleagues, and understand that the amount that I can learn working in a team will far superseded the knowledge gained working as a solo developer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer (Freelance) Gekofx Photography - Detroit, M - 2018-Present

Here I worked side by side with a photographer building a platform to be used to upload photos and collections of photos for their portfolio. I planned executed the most reasonable system design for the requirements described, as well as implemented the standard HTTP CRUD functionality and pagination system. I also set up and managed multiple development environments for easy sandbox testing and implementation of new features that could be seen before deployed into production.

Back House Manager Chipotle Grill - Southfield, MI - 2018-Present

Here I am a back of house manager that oversees the handling and preparation of food and materials from the truck until it gets to our customers. I heavily enforce sanitation protocol and ensure that our crew members properly adapt to any unforeseen circumstances such as an overnight catering order request. I also consistently give impromptu training and demonstrations to make sure our staff is comfortable in performing the required tasks and to make sure they have fun while doing so.